English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
1987.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
First-line index
First-line index to English-language verse in manuscripts held in the Houghton Library that date from the Anglo-Saxon period to the nineteenth century.
1 collection
Manuscripts acquired from various sources at various times.
There are no restrictions on physical access to this material. Collection is open for research.
Organized in the following series: I. First line index; and II. Register of manuscripts.
This first-line index to English-language verse in manuscripts held at the Houghton Library, Harvard University includes verse, dating from the Anglo-Saxon period to the nineteenth century, and poems written by authors born before 1800 (such as John Keats) in manuscript anthologies, commonplace books, and cother collections, as well as single sheets.
How to use this index:
Poems are cited by first line as it appears in the manuscripts as given as well as when it is incomplete and ends imperfectly. When the first line of a partial poem is not metrically complete, the citation also includes the next succeeding line. Poems found incomplete in Houghton manuscripts are thus marked in the index. First lines are alphabetized word for word, including definite and indefinite articles. For alphabetization, the first line is usually spelled according to modern orthography; exceptions are Anglo-Saxon verse, where the aesc, eth, thorn, and yok have been transliterated, and Middle English and Scots, which have been copied as they appeared in the manuscripts.
Each first line is followed by a Houghton manuscript call number, followed (when applicable) by a roman numeral to indicate the volume of the manuscript in which the poem appears. The remaining number indicates the folio, folder, or page in that manuscript. For example, "A Belgian Hanks of noted rank (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 56v" means that a partial extract, beginning with that line, will be found in volume ii, folio 56v of MS Eng 612. However, some Houghton manuscripts are not foliated. For loose leaves, the location of a verse within a manuscript cannot be specified. For bound but unfoliated manuscripts, Seng himself counted the foliation.
This index includes manuscripts in the Library's collection that were cataloged at the time Peter Seng compiled it (about 1980). The index has not been maintained.
All items described in this index are cataloged in detail in individual records in HOLLIS or in other collection finding aids in OASIS. Search in HOLLIS or OASIS by call number to retrieve these descriptions.
A
A baker in the town o' Ayr MS Eng 1491 (3), 12
A band of gypsies all in a road (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxvii, 825
A barren soil where nature's germs confined (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 8
A beautiful creature with her parents did dwell MS Eng 1471, v, 117v
A beauty smoother than an ivory plain MS Eng 686, 65
A beauty smoother than the ivory plain MS Eng 686, 72v
A beauty's birthday, heaven and earth MS Eng 723.1 (4)
A bed of roses! Castlereagh's in fun MS Eng 569.65, 35v
A Belgian Hanks of noted rank (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 56v
A better mason than Lammikin MS Eng 1486 (3), 60
A bill upon my grave I see MS Eng 247.5, 32
A bitter death, a suffocating death (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 72
A bold intruder with a brazen face MS Am 1177, 2
A bold virago, stout and tall MS Eng 1132, 5
A bone, God wot, sticks in my throat, without I have a draught MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 53v
A bonny lad there was MS Eng 512, 16; MS Eng 1491 (3), 63
A bonny lass is my delight MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 99
A bonny May went up the street (incomplete) MS Eng 862, 271
A bonny young lassie there lives in this town MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 173v
A brazen tow'r, guarded with strong-barr'ed doors MS Eng 640, 29
A bribe! The worth of three kingdoms I defy (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 5
A brutish indolence many men doth bind MS Eng 614, 101v
A burning blush o'er all my face has got (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 49v
A cadger braw came to this town MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 81
A Calliconian next appears (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 80
A captive sad, in sorrow bowed (incomplete) MS Eng 569.66, 48
A caudle for the gentleman; He'll did o' th' pip else (incomplete) Autograph file, A: Washington Allston, iii, 33v
A certain man called Adam MS Eng 247.5, 24v
A certain old cook called his dog cuckold MS Eng 686, 33v
A chance religious minstre wife (incomplete) MS Am 2349, ii, p. 238
A change in all ensues, the winter's cold MS Am 1919, 27
A cheerful answer glads a troubled heart MS Eng 639, 4v
A child knew well a jar that stood MS Thr 198, folder 39
A child of art, assuming nature's hue MS Keats 3.13, i, tipped in at folio 14
A church bell tolls a melancholy sound MS Keats 3.5, p. 19
A city set upon a hill MS Eng 247.5, 21
A clerk there was of Oxenford also (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 21v
A cobbler and a curate once disputed MS Eng 121, 2v
A cobbler there was, and he lived in a stall MS Eng 512, 81; MS Eng 629, 70
A cock laird so cadgie MS Eng 512, 55v
A coke they had with hem for the nones (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 29v
A collar, a collar, our king 'gan cry (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxix, 998
A common fame doth Preston fill: the court MS Eng 699, 27
A company of guards we found MS Eng 611, ii, 20
A conscience clear is worth a world of treasure (incomplete) MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 81 tipped in
A cornice round the gateway goes (incomplete) MS Eng 569.66, 60v
A country lass, for such was she here MS Eng 612, ii, 50v
A country state MS Eng 612, ii, 48v
A courtier's tongue for flattery MS Eng 612, iii, 98
A crop of honor 'tis he reaps MS Eng 645, 19
A crown of ivy! I submit my head MS Keats *EC8.K2262. 817p(D), leaf preceding the title-page
A curse attends that woman's love MS Eng 1038.1, 50v
A damsel, I'm told, of a delicate mold MS Eng 512, 65v
A deeper peace than in the deserts found (incomplete) MS Eng 327, "To S. Wilkinson, Sept. 21"; 389
A dialogue I chance to hear as I a-musing stood MS Eng 834, folder 1
A doleful time of weeping tears MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 167
A due reflection on our state MS Eng 680, 58
A dusty wife's daughter MS Eng 1491 (3), 23v
A face deformed a vizard fair doth hide MS Typ 14, 91
A fair country and vines also (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 4
A fair maid sat in her bower door MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 64v
A fair maid went into the corn (incomplete) MS Am 2349, xxii, 233
A fair there is whose well-earned happy lot MS Eng 1316, 1
A fairer face of evening cannot be (incomplete) *EC8. W8915.838s, p. 34
A fairer person lost not heaven; he seemed (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, ii, 94v
A famous assembly was summoned of late MS Eng 629, 26
A famous poetess has lately writ MS Eng 633, 75v
A farmer there lived in the North Country MS Am 2349, xxi, 79
A fast rays it drives into a stound (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A fellow that was troubled with a wife (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 49
A fencer and a roaring boy late meeting MS Eng 247.5, 44v
A firm accord in forces that are weak MS Eng 614, 99v
A fisherman he had been in his youth (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 130
A flower was offered to me MS Eng 1167, 58; MS Eng 1167, 70; MS Eng 889, 48
A foe's miscarriage speak not, tho' you know MS Eng 614, 99v
A fool and knave with diff'rent views MS Keats 3.13, i, 14v
A founder of new fashions The revolution of all shapes and habits (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
A fox, in life's extreme decay MS Eng 1038.2, 34v
A fox may steal your hens, sir MS Eng 1038.1, 49; MS Eng 895, 64
A frankeleyn there was in his companye (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 25v
A Freeman and yet no man MS Eng 686, 13
A freeman yet no man MS Eng 686, 86v
A Frere there was, a wanton and a mery (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 17v
A friend o' mine came here yestreen MS Eng 1486 (3), 10
A friend sequester'd in a land remote MS Eng 680, 10v
A frog he would a-wooing go, heigh ho, said Rowly MS Thr 198, folder 140
A gallant younker in this land MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 126
A gard'ner of peculiar taste MS Eng 1038.2, 52v
A garrison? What else dost thou not here MS Eng 645, 13v
A generous friendship no cold medium knows (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 78; MS Keats 3.13, i, 79v
A gentle Manciple there was of the temple (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 43v
A gentleman came o'er the sea MS Eng 1471, i, 17
A giant, sprung from the giant-race, who took (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 114v
A glorious, new, prophetic star MS Eng 629, 86v
A glorious people vibrated again (incomplete) *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 19v
A godly maiden with one of her society MS Eng 686, 54v
A good man many wrongs and failings brooks MS Eng 614, 102
A good man there was of Relygyoun (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 37v
A good persuasion more and more improve MS Eng 614, 98v
A good specimen gives his own history (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A good wyfe there was besyde Bathe (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 35v
A governor so just, so rare MS Thr 198, folder 32
A great lord of late fell out with a thing MS Eng 629, 16v
A great man living holds much ground; the brim MS Eng 606, 14v
A Grecian scoff is a wracking wheel (incomplete) MS Eng 1167, 7
A grove I reach'd, where tuneful throstles sung (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 135v
A haunting music, sole perhaps and lone (incomplete) MS Keats 1.63, 1; MS Keats 2.25
A heavy-laden cable-train Autograph file, B: William Horace Brown, 1
A hell on earth, the afflicted mind dismayed (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 3
A herald of arms there was sent MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 7v tipped in
A high desire, no speed, too early brings MS Eng 614, 96v
A homely hut, a rural cave MS Eng 611, ii, 7v
A horse chewing on the bridle in the stable is but idle MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 25
A huge fellowThat prose compound cannot but defile (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A hundred and one by fifty divide MS Eng 569.67, 37; MS Eng 569.67, 36
A hungry vulture fastening on his prey MS Eng 569.68, 6v
A husband and a wife oft disagreeing MS Eng 121, 6
A jolly shepherd that sat on Zion hill MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 98; MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 102
A juggler long through all the town MS Eng 1038.2, 46
A knight, landed knight came from the North Land MS Am 2349, xxi, 25
A Knight there was and that a worthy man (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 7v
A lad and a lass met on the green MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 212v
A laddie and a lassie dwelt in the south country MS Eng 1497, ii, 159v
A lady lately that was fully sped MS Eng 686, 55
A lady looked out at her castle wa' MS Eng 1486 (3), 51
A lady once lived but a mile from an oak *82-408, 130
A lady that a kiss doth take MS Eng 1323, 47
A Lancashire farmer who had a fair wife MS Eng 1491 (3), 33
A lass that was loaden with care MS Eng 512, 36v
A lassie was laden with care MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 185v
A lassie went out in an evening clear MS Am 2349, xxii, 231; MS Am 2349, xxii, 232
A laystall this, Apollo spoke the word MS Eng 606, 42v
A leaden sword within a golden sheath MS Typ 14, 71
A life replete with grief the gods decree (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 7v
A linnet's nest with anxious care MS Thr 198, folder 34
A lion tired with state affairs MS Eng 1038.2, 13v
A little black thing among the snow MS Eng 1167, 54
A little did my mother ken (incomplete) MS Eng 1470, 123
A little learning, twenty grains of sense MS Eng 629, 118v
A little longer yeta little longer MS Eng 1094, 66; MS Eng 1094, 67
A little shallop floating near the shore (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 127
A little shallop, floating there hard by (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 103
A little time I dwell below MS Eng 614, 32
A little 'tis, a poor man's want sustains MS Eng 614, 99v
A load of guts wrapt in a sallow skin MS Eng 633, 81v
A long, long kiss, a kiss of youth and love (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 83
A long preludium, where the matter's full MS Eng 633, 28v; MS Eng 585, 145
A louse without license a man does molest MS Eng 686, 12
A lovely being, scarcely formed or moulded (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 63
A lovely flower cropped in its prime MS Am 929, 86v
A lovely maid to a friar came MS Eng 512, 29v; MS Eng 1491 (3), 64
A lover ne'er despairing MS Eng 512, 8
A lover's passion rightly to declare MS Eng 614, 99
A lowly cottage, underneath a hill MS Eng 614, 81v
A lusty swain was cleaving of a block MS Eng 686, 34v
A maid called Peggie MS Eng 1491 (3), 61
A maid is like the golden oar MS Eng 1038.1, 48
A man had some few days been ill MS Eng 629, 132
A man I sing whom memory reveres (incomplete) MS Keats 3.4, 20; MS Keats 3.4, 44
A man of bus'ness won't till ev'ning dine (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 122v
A man so lost In the wild ways of passion, that he's sensible (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A mangled corse. She must not know my fate (incomplete) MS Eng 265.2, folder 1
A marbled Caesar pinnion'd to a throne (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 52
A Marchaunt there was, with a longe berde (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 19v
A merchant of London, as many report MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 111
A mighty lion, lord of all the wood MS Eng 266, 79
A mighty lion, lord of all the wood (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 20
A mighty spire whose top doth pierce the sky MS Typ 14, 7
A mighty window hollow in the center MS Eng 630, 3
A milder horror let the muse explore MS Eng 611, i, 18
A mirror that the toilette graced MS Thr 198, folder 39
A mist arose, as from a scummy marsh (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 95
A mistress I've lost it is true MS Eng 692, 56
A mittimus, a warrant, a release MS Eng 228, 4
A modish upstart pesterer of the town MS Eng 247.5, 74
A moment, doubtful of the sound (incomplete) MS Eng 265.1, folder 9
A moment more Our feet were soft in flowers. Hurry o'er (incomplete) MS Keats 3.2, 238
A monk there was, faire for the maistrie (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 15v
A monkey, to reform the times MS Eng 1038.2, 20v
A monster in the course of vice grown old MS Eng 768 (vol. 2), 19v
A mother dead! and am I from the throne MS Eng 629, 57
A mother who vast pleasure finds MS Eng 1038.2, 4v
A mystery Somewhat above our art (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A new Nercissus I admire MS Eng 630, 21v
A Newcastle man with a Hall man fell in MS Thr 198, folder 47
A noble young squire that liv'd in the west MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 100
A novice gallant that beyond the seas MS Eng 247.5, 3v
A nymph and a swain to Apollo once prayed MS Eng 895, 63v
A nymph whenas the summer beams MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. ii, p. 138
A page, a knight, a baronet, and an earl MS Eng 686, 10
A palace that is more uneasy far (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 74
A pale dream came to a lady fair MS Eng 258.3, 4
A paltry wretch he had, half-starved MS Eng 1132, 3
A paper book is sent by Boyle MS Eng 629, 129
A papist dwelling to a Brownist near MS Eng 121, 2v
A peace, a peace, whilst every one doth seek MS Eng 645, 14v
A petty sneaking knave I knew MS Eng 1167, 15; MS Eng 1167, 77; MS Eng 889, 8
A pilgrim truly here I am MS Eng 614, 47v
A pin who long had served a beauty MS Eng 1038.2, 23
A place there is most solemn to the sight MS Eng 623
A plain built house, after so long a stay MS Thr 32, 1
A plain there was, called life, extended wide MS Eng 612, ii, 122
A pleasant grove In which were oakis great, straight as a line (incomplete) MS Eng 731, folder 275, 30
A poet, starving in a garret (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 97
A sailor courted a farmer's daughter MS Eng 1471, v, 90v
A sailor courted a lovely damsel MS Eng 1471, v, 66v
A single rose is shedding there (incomplete) MS Eng 1471, v, 87
A poet's rage And stretched metre of an antique song (incomplete) MS Keats 3.3, p. 51
A politician is the devil's quilted anvil (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 5v
A poor court-bankrupt, outwitted and lost (incomplete) MS Keats 2.24.2
A poor man's name choose rather to abide MS Eng 614, 101v
A poor old man weighed down with years MS Eng 971, 2
A pow'r so vast and so egregious (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 40
A power that never ceased to abide in him (incomplete) MS Eng 327 (4), p. 2
A pox of the fooling and plotting MS Eng 633, 58v
A pox on the times, let them go as ye will, tho' the taxes are grown so heavy MS Eng 1038.1, 28
A pox upon Britain took George for their king MS Eng 1471, vi, 33
A primrose by the river's brim MS Eng 1461, 69
A prince, within the circle of whose mind (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 86
A proper new ballad which without any fail MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 43 tipped in
A proud and spangled sir (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A proud and spangled sir, That looks three handfuls higher than his foretop (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A queen, great Dima's daughter, Priam's wife (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 13v
A rake, by every passion ruled MS Eng 1038.2, 36
A rattling, roaring Willie MS Eng 1497, ii, 98v
A raw young fellow; One never train'd up in arms, but rather fashion'd (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 34
A reverend and esteemed divine (incomplete) MS Am 2349, ii, p. 238
A reverend sage, of learning most profound MS Typ 14, 12v
A robe of seeming truth and trust MS Am 1428 (168)
A rogue that played then more false pranks (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 43
A rueful will! Behold too lost to sense (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A sacrifice to thee, O Lord, is due MS Eng 625, 209
A sail! a saila promised prize to hope (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 65
A satyr once did run away for dread MS Eng 1494, 6
A seaman of Dover, whose excellent parts MS Eng 895, 87v; MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 127
A second part I bring you here MS Eng 895, 73
A secret seldom seen, that women counsel keep MS Eng 686, 14
A sensitive plant in a garden grew *EC8. Sh445. 929n, 1
A Sergiaunt of Lawe, ware and wyse (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 23v
A sessions was held the other day MS Eng 703, 70
A shoemaker (an odd conceited clown) MS Eng 247.5, 42v
A shipman was there, wonning fer by west (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 31v
A sickly taper, glimmering feeble rays (incomplete) MS Eng 611, i, 8
A sickness sore that doth in secret wound MS Typ 14, 96
A silly John, surprised with joy MS Eng 966.1, 24v; MS Eng 686, 37v
A silly poor shepherd MS Eng 520, 42
A silly shepherd lately sat MS Eng 1495, 11v
A simple solitary flower MS Eng 1461, 201
A skillful leader, stout, severe MS Eng 1132, 3
A slender Young waiting damsel to attend her (incomplete) MS Eng 1132, 5
A slow tongue betokens modesty MS Eng 686, 12v
A snake which used in privacy to dwell MS Eng 611, i, 12v
A snarling cur did in the manger lie MS Typ 14, 36
A sneaking cur, the master spies MS Eng 1038.2, 31v
A soldier must be stout and void of fear MS Eng 614, 100
A soldier should his enemy prevent MS Eng 247.5, 4v
A solemn feast great Jupiter did make MS Typ 14, 9
A solemn hush of spirit, he beholds (incomplete) MS Eng 947, a.l.s. to Cottle
A Sompnour there was with us in that place (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 47v
A star of late appeared in Virgo's train MS Eng 686, 52
A stone is found, which is not dear MS Eng 1488, 51
A storm that doth all things prostrate (incomplete) MS Eng 265.2, folder 4
A strange erratum in all the editions MS Eng 1167, 17; MS Eng 889, 10
A stranger coming to the town MS Eng 686, 33v
A striking clock the hour declares (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 4
A suit, ye gods, since ye alone can tell MS Am 1369, 1
A sword and a charm, two good essentials MS Thr 198, folder 40
A sword is waving o'er the land MS Eng 1227, 57v
A table richly spread in regal mode (incomplete) MS Lowell 6, 2
A tale it is such as bears (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A tale which may content the minds (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A temper not too soon offended MS Keats 3.13, i, 16
A thankful heart hath earned one favor twice (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 139
A thirsty dog to Nilus runs to drink MS Typ 14, 38
A thousand and six and sixty years MS Eng 628, 52v
A thousand deaths I'd rather choose to die (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 98v
A thousand years five hundred and four score MS Eng 757, 2v
A tower of brass, doors strongly barred (incomplete) MS Eng 631, 5v
A trader on the sea to riches grew MS Am 567, 22
A tragical story I have to relate MS Eng 895, 93v
A treat so copious, so immense a mind (incomplete) MS Eng 612, ii, 64
A trifling story you'll hear MS Eng 512, 38
A trinitarian to a Johnian said MS Eng 569.63, 33v
A troop of soldiers in Edinburgh MS Eng 1491 (3), 50v
A truce, ye devils, take possession MS Thr 198, folder 40
A true friend's love must like a chimney be MS Eng 686, 13
A true friend's love must like a privy be MS Eng 686, 13
A trumpeter the captain's captive led MS Typ 14, 76
A tumor's raised in counsels rumps MS Eng 645, 37
A [ ] upon a straw MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. iii, p. 4v
A very pretty fancy, a brave gallant show MS Eng 1038.1, 27v
A victory!... It will pluck out all grey hair (incomplete) MS Eng 1274, ch. 33
A virgin fair and pure four lustre's old MS Eng 228, 4
A virgin most pure as the prophet doth tell MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, 1767, 9
A virgin most pure as the prophets doth tell MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 4
A virgin most pure the prophet doth tell MS Eng 1507, John Webb: his book, 1777, 9
virgin once there was, whom heav'n design'd (incomplete) MS Eng 612, iii, 101v
A virgin once was walking along MS Eng 895, 28
A virgin unspotted the prophet foretold MS Eng 1507, Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], 27
A virgin's life who would be leaving MS Eng 612, ii, 49
A virtuous lady, sitting in a muse MS Eng 686, 34v
A virtuous young lady ingenious and fair MS Eng 895, 5v
A vizor and a mask are whispering rooms (incomplete) MS Eng 611, iii, 3
A waving sea of heads was round me spread (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 98
A weary body's blithe when the sun gangs down MS Eng 1497, i, 14v
A wedding, a wedding, a wedding ye kenn'd MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 222v
A wee bird cam to our ha' door MS Eng 1497, i, 50v
A well-spent hour gives every one content MS Eng 520, 106
A while rash fair, forget your gay delights MS Eng 834, folder 2
A wife's like a guinea in gold (incomplete) MS Eng 616, i, 18v
A wig that's full, ane empty scull MS Eng 512, 68v
A windmill fair that all things had to grind MS Typ 14, 36v
A wolf with hunger fierce and bold MS Eng 1038.2, 24
A woman at St. James's MS Eng 616, i, 14
A woman's goodness when she is a wife (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2 (twice)
A woman's rule should be in such a fashion (incomplete) MS Eng 686, 97v; MS Eng 616, i, 28
A woman's ware, like china MS Eng 616, i, 14
A wonder, world! be't for thy eight enrolled MS Eng 699, 26
A word is ringing through my brain MS Am 1428 (168)
A word must be added, and then I have done MS Eng 926, 57
A word once said, Adam was made MS Eng 1503 (3), vol. i, p. 40
A word once spoke MS Eng 639, 20
A wound full of measure MS Eng 686, 49
A yeoman had he and servants no mo (incomplete) MS Typ 560, 11v
A young cook married was on Monday last MS Eng 686, 33v
A young L. gained my heart MS Eng 512, 92v
A young man came to my bower door MS Eng 1491 (4), i, 145v; MS Eng 1491 (3), 42
A young physician (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A young physicianThat letting God alone, ascribes to Nature (incomplete) MS Eng 265.6, v. 2
A youth once free and happy, now a slave MS Eng 602, 57
A youthful prince in prime of lusty years MS Typ 14, 15v
A zealous locksmith died of late MS Eng 686, 54v
A' the skippers of bonny Lothain MS Eng 1498, 18
A' ye who daily sigh and pray (incomplete) MS Am 2349, ii, p. 238
Abhorred silence first invades the ear (incomplete) MS Keats 3.13, i, 65
Abhorred the man, whom fate ordains, in spite MS Eng 611, ii, 103
Abou Ben Adhem (may his tribe increase!) Autograph file, H: Leigh Hunt, 1
About the age of twenty-six MS Eng 1491 (4), ii, 219v
About the arrow swift Echeneis slow doth fold MS Typ 14, 74
About the time that I shall be (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 26v
About this Sir Isaac folks made a great pother MS Eng 569.63, 35v
About Yule when the wind blew cool MS Am 2349, xxiv, 395; MS Eng 1497, i, 157
Above his neighbors he exalts his horn (incomplete) MS Eng 611, ii, 70v